Jordan Moore

💌 jordanmoore753@gmail.com 👂 Croton-on-Hudson, NY 🤘 https://jordanmoore.dev/

Profile

Software engineer with experience building fast, scalable cloud applications. Experience with JavaScript, Ruby, PostgreSQL, Docker, Rails, and React. Former educator and M.Ed.

Skills

Backend Node.js, Rails, Ruby, PostgreSQL, GraphQL & RESTful APIs, Docker

Frontend JavaScript, React/Redux, HTML/CSS, jQuery

Tooling Git, Linux, Pivotal Tracker

Digital Ocean, Heroku, Google Cloud Platform

Cloud

Professional Experience

Co-Creator, Software Engineer, Satellite

2020 - present

https://satellite-baas.github.io/

Satellite is a multi-instance backend-as-a-service (BaaS) that provides the essential features of data persistence, frontend hosting, and a GraphQL API without the complexities of managing and configuring servers. Built with Node.js, Express, Kubernetes, Docker, React, and DGraph.

- Prototyped and built the application using Node.js, nginx, Dgraph, Docker, and Kubernetes
- Simplified deployment of backend instances by using a graph database to automate GraphQL API generation
- Designed the Admin GUI for managing and deploying backend instances using React
- Integrated the Admin GUI with backend instances and the Kubernetes cluster
- Implemented Traefik as a Kubernetes Ingress controller to enable creation of new backend instances without manual routing or TLS configuration
- Tested the application's multi-instance deployment on several cloud providers (Digital Ocean, Azure, GCP)
- Worked with a remote team
- Co-authored technical case study: https://satellite-baas.github.io/#case-study

Full Stack Web Developer, Self-Employed

2019 - 2020

Remote. Built open-source projects using Ruby, JavaScript, Node.js, SQL, React, HTML/CSS, and Express.

- DS-Plus: an NPM package built with JavaScript that provides fast, non-native data structures
- Regexer: a Regex editor that evaluates Ruby and JavaScript expressions, built with React and Ruby
- Mello: a Trello clone built in React and Redux with a Rails API backend that supports creating, editing, and deleting boards, lists, and cards

Educator, Various Districts

2014 - 2018

Subjects taught: Web Development, Mathematics, AP Psychology, US History

Education

Launch School, https://launchschool.com/employers	2019 – 2020
Multi-year Software Engineering curriculum focused on mastering web development fundamentals	
Roberts Wesleyan College, M.Ed Childhood Education	2013 – 2014
State University of New York at Geneseo, BA Philosophy	2010 - 2013